<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cockatrice_carddatabase version="4">
	<sets>
		<set>
			<name>CDC</name>
			<longname>Custom Dindungus Commander</longname>
			<settype>Custom</settype>
		</set>
	</sets>
	<cards>
		<card>
			<name>Nitwit, Average Tourist</name>
			<text>Trample, haste
Ward - Sacrifice a nonbasic land.
When Nitwit enters or attacks, you may sacrifice an equipment or aura enchantment attached to it. If you do not, you may sacrifice an untapped, non-attacking creature, If you sacrifice a permanent this way, Nitwit deals X damage to any target then you may draw X cards and lose X life where X is Nitwit's power.</text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Goblin Civilian</type>
				<manacost>{B/R}{R/G}</manacost>
				<cmc>2</cmc>
				<color>BRG</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>1/1</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/dj8pdUU.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Jace, of Bottomless Pockets</name>
			<text>Cumulative upkeep — mill 1
When Jace enters or leaves the battlefield, place all cards you own in exile and in your graveyard at the bottom of your library in a random order.
If a card you own would be put in your graveyard or into exile, put it on the bottom of your library instead.
At the beginning of your end step, If every card you own other than Jace is in your hand or in play, you win the game.</text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Human Wizard</type>
				<manacost>UU</manacost>
				<cmc>2</cmc>
				<color>U</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>1/4</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/LzWs2ob.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Self-Loathing</name>
			<text>Flying
Ward — Pay 5 life.
Spells and abilities affect you as though you were an opponent.
When Self-Loathing enters, spells and abilities affect you as though you were an opponent until end of turn.
Evoke {2}</text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Elemental Incarnation</type>
				<manacost>1UB{R/G}</manacost>
				<cmc>4</cmc>
				<color>UBRG</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>1/5</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/JsiSWHT.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Leon, The Rule Bender</name>
			<text>Eminence: At the beginning of the game you create a "Leon's Terms and Conditions" emblem.
(Inked card — an inked card is a card that its owner either controls on the battlefield or a card they own in exile with an ink counter on it.)
+1: You may remove up to three words from the textbox of an inked card.
-3: You may add the word "when", "whenever" or "at" to the textbox of an inked card. You may then add up to four words to that card's textbox that define the trigger.
-7: You may remove all words from the textbox of an inked card. If you do, add five words to that card's text box from among words removed this way.
Leon can be your commander.</text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Planeswalker</type>
				<manacost>2WWUU</manacost>
				<cmc>6</cmc>
				<color>WU</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<loyalty>5</loyalty>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/CotGwaZ.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>1</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Leon's Terms and Conditions</name>
			<text>Commander Permanents you own and control named Leon, The Rule Bender gain:
"You may cast spells from exile with ink counters on them. When you cast a spell this way, it retains changes made by Leon on the stack.
If a triggered ability of a permanent you control triggers and that permanent has triggered three times this turn, or if the spell or ability would cause you to win the game, instead counter that ability, this ability cannot be countered.
Cards cast and abilities altered by Leon must resolve as written. If no clear ruling can be made, they have no effect.
0: You may reveal a card from your hand. Exile the revealed card with an ink counter on it. Activate only as a sorcery."</text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Emblem</type>
			</prop>
			<set picURL="https://i.imgur.com/W2hpfIQ.png"/>
			<tablerow>1</tablerow>
			<reverse-related>Leon, The Rule Bender</reverse-related>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Luxia, Angel of Prosperity</name>
			<text>Creatures you control have lifelink.
Whenever you gain life, draw that many cards.
As long as you have at least 40 more life than your starting life total, creatures you control have base power and toughness equal to your life total.
{X}{W}{U}{t} You gain X life. </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Angel</type>
				<manacost>WWUU</manacost>
				<cmc>4</cmc>
				<color>WU</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>2/2</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/y8QsgqC.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Era, Timekeeper</name>
			<text>Indestructible
As long as your devotion to white and blue is less than seven, Era isn’t a creature.
At the beginning of each player’s upkeep, that player takes an extra turn after this one. 
If a player would take an extra turn after taking an extra turn, skip that turn instead.
Era, Timekeeper cannot be phased out. </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Enchantment Creature — God</type>
				<manacost>2WU</manacost>
				<cmc>4</cmc>
				<color>WU</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>3/4</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/XrSnfDP.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		
		<card>
			<name>Roaming Legends</name>
			<text>Other nonland permanents are Legendary. The same is true for spells and nonland permanents that aren’t on the battlefield.
Legendary instant and sorcery spells cost (2) less to cast.
Whenever you cast a legendary spell during your turn, choose one: 
•  Amass Shapeshifters 1. 
•  Target creature gains deathtouch until end of turn. 
•  Create a token that’s a copy of target creature you control. </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Shapeshifter Army</type>
				<manacost>2UBR</manacost>
				<cmc>5</cmc>
				<color>UBR</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>2/2</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/fcpY1Sj.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Just a Little Turtle</name>
			<text>Hexproof, Indestructible
You gain “Ward {-} choose another target.” </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Turtle Wizard</type>
				<manacost>1WWWR</manacost>
				<cmc>5</cmc>
				<color>WR</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>1/3</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/pDYTuaS.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
				<card>
			<name>Eye of Tomorrow</name>
			<text>You may cast non-instant spells as though they had flash.
You may only cast instant spells as a sorcery.
Instant spells you cast gain “Addendum {-} If you cast this spell during your main phase, it deals 1 damage to any target” </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Artifact Creature — Eye Construct</type>
				<manacost>URW</manacost>
				<cmc>3</cmc>
				<color>URW</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>2/4</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/QiTVZjf.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Centuris</name>
			<text>Whenever you cast a spell from exile, time travel.
{1} Exile a nonland card from your hand: Put time counters on the exiled card equal to its mana value. If it doesn’t have suspend, it gains suspend. </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Weird</type>
				<manacost>1UUR</manacost>
				<cmc>4</cmc>
				<color>UR</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>2/3</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/kL3dkIe.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
				<card>
			
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Cheeky Bastard</name>
			<text>Flash
When this creature enters, your opponents cannot lose the game this turn.
{R}{B} Sacrifice this creature. Your opponents cast a copy of the next spell you cast this turn.  </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Pirate Wizard</type>
				<manacost>1WB</manacost>
				<cmc>3</cmc>
				<color>WB</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>3/3</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/vDLhdyg.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
		
		<card>
			<name>Freedom</name>
			<text>(1): Manifest a card from your hand. Any player may activate this ability. {i}(Put it onto the battlefield face down as a 2/2 creature. Turn it face up any time for its mana cost if it's a creature card.){/i} 

Exile a face-down permanent you control face up: You may play that card this turn. {i}(You still pay its costs. Timing rules still apply.){/i}  </text>
			<prop>
				<type>Legendary Creature — Avatar</type>
				<manacost>GUR</manacost>
				<cmc>3</cmc>
				<color>GUR</color>
				<layout>normal</layout>
				<pt>3/3</pt>
				<format-standard>legal</format-standard>
			</prop>
			<set rarity="common" picURL="https://i.imgur.com/cC0SMTK.png">CDC</set>
			<tablerow>2</tablerow>
		</card>
	</cards>
</cockatrice_carddatabase>